*eerie music*
*music turns restless*
There.
*SA men talking and laughing*
*prisoner coughing*
*loud gunshot*
*SA men laugh*
*uneasy murmuring*
Well?
What is going on?
*multiple gunshots ring out*
*man cries out*
What are they doing?
(Brock) They'll be here any second.
*gunshot rings out*
Make yourself invisible.
Why?
(SA Man) One for me!
Go on!
- I'm doing it!
*gunshot*
(SA Man) Again!
*man groans in agony*
*SA men laugh*
*man gasps for air*
You can take him!
- Clean hit!
*man continues groaning*
(Matern) Brock? It's Brock!
- It is Brock.
(Matern) I have to get closer.
Hold on, comrade.
(Heymann) Brock, we need you.
- (Mandel) Light!
*Brock breathes frantically*
I must stop the bleeding.
Easy. Easy now.
(Prisoner) Press hard. Harder.
Hang in there!
Hey, otherwise he'll bleed to death.
- Harder.
*eerie music*
*rhythmic music*
*doorbell rings*
Frau Helfers, what a pleasure.
Frau Luxemburg.
- Come on in.
*she clears her throat*
Is she here?
No, but I expect
Dr. Völcker will arrive shortly.
Ah.
I baked some doughnuts.
My sister's recipe.
(Behnke) Yes, N, as in North Pole,
Natalia, and of course 'Luxenburg'.
'Natalia', and of course 'Luxenburg'.
Aha, really?
I didn't know that.
- It's not important anyway.
Only our grandfather,
on my father's side,
one of the wealthiest merchants
in the Kingdom of Poland,
he's still turning in his grave today
because his name is no longer spelled right.
*clock ticking*
I'll brew another pot.
*door opens and closes*
*indistinct whispering*
(Behnke) I can't keep her here
for hours on end.
Tell her about the family,
or about Liebknecht.
I know nothing about him,
except that he was a daredevil.
*doorbell rings*
That's her, that must be her.
*Litten cries out*
Herr Katelbach? Herr Litten?
What kind of charade is this?
Who are you?
*doorbell rings*
That is surely Dr. Völcker.
Come along, Frau Helfers,
we'll await you in the parlor.
Under no circumstances do I wish
to be part of this farce.
Allow us to explain.
- It was the only way.
You are two figures of great influence.
And open-minded.
- Quiet now!
*knocking*
(Völcker) Hello?
Please.
Please. Come in.
- Let me be, please.
(whispers) Yes.
- After you.
Frau Völcker, what a joy.
Comrade, if you don't mind.
Comrade Völcker,
of course.
Is Frau Helfers here?
- Yes.
Please, come in.
May I?
- No.
Where is Helfers?
I'll go... There she is already.
She is no Luxemburg.
I know.
Very well.
Yet I am Elisabeth Behnke.
*somber music*
You may revile me and damn me,
yet everything I do and have done,
is done with a pure heart
and genuine purpose.
Surely we are united by the same goal.
The enemy stands
before his greatest triumph.
Only by your union
can he still be stopped.
You can steer the destiny of this country now,
or out of false pride
surrender our beloved land
to its destruction.
'Men make their own history,
not of their own free will,
yet they make it themselves.'
(whispers) Outstanding!
With a Luxemburg quote.
World-class!
You ought to start a party.
They're talking to each other.
Damn it. Do you have another?
- No, mine are all gone too.
(Katelbach) I'll take care of that.
Wait, if you're going anyway,
I'll write a grocery list.
Things in there could take a while.
You dictate, I'll write.
(Newsboy) Berliner Morgenpost!
Berliner Morgenpost!
*typewriters clattering, murmuring*
Chief Inspector,
you wanted to speak with me?
Yes, Miss Ritter.
I expect your report by the lunch break.
Which report?
The report on the Forster case
and the disappearance
of the suspended Inspector Rath.
Give me Identification.
We should close the book on this case quickly.
Yes, Gennat speaking.
One moment.
Excuse me.
*measured music*
*door opens*
*prisoners coughing*
Rath!
Rath, Gereon!
Step forward!
Here, take this.
Here.
Come along.
*music turns darker*
*cell door is locked*
Looks like you and I have to do
the dirty work now.
*music swells dramatically*
*he groans with exertion*
*lamp hums*
*ominous music*
*bell rings, latch clicks*
(Gennat) Come in.
*music ends dramatically*
My report, Chief Inspector.
*he clears his throat*
How can you simply drop this investigation?
You taught me that we let no one
meddle in our work
in the execution of our duty.
You hammered into us to make no distinction
between a corporate director
and a vagrant.
You spoke of human dignity
as inviolable.
Now you sit behind your desk
and abandon one of your finest men?
Meanwhile, they are pressuring Böhm
because his investigation
threatens the Chancellor.
What on earth is the matter with you,
damn it all?
What is this?
A Prosecutor Dresse reached out
regarding the medical file.
He is in Berlin.
Apparently trying to obtain a visa
for the United States.
You spoke with him...
I only made a phone call,
nothing more.
He will meet you.
I noted down the time and place.
Now if you will excuse me,
I have work to do.
*mysterious music*
Thank you.
*trap clacks*
*echoing gunshot*
Surely you see that you backed
the wrong horse.
So far all I see is you trying
to get me back into your boat,
my dear Herr Schleicher.
Yet Hitler cannot be controlled.
Yes, it may seem that way,
yet with money, anyone can be controlled.
Others have fallen victim
to that fallacy before.
Hitler is an enemy of capital.
You were Reich Chancellor once.
You had your chance.
This time Hindenburg followed Hitler,
not you.
That's democracy for you.
(dismissive) Democracy.
Nyssen, now listen here.
What we need is a national-right pact
against Hitler,
with you and the leading industrialists,
with the German Nationals,
reasonable men from the NSDAP,
with the military.
And with my money?
Yes, with your money.
I promise you,
it is the best investment you'll ever make.
That sounds intriguing.
*trap clacks*
*echoing gunshot*
Congratulations, Director,
a direct hit.
Herr Former Reich Chancellor.
What is it?
Your wife asks that you join her.
She has news of the utmost importance.
You will excuse me.
*door opens*
*footsteps*
What is it?
I reached Minister Göring.
And?
It's on.
When?
February 27th. Firmly confirmed.
What if he fails to show again,
stands us up once more?
It is the first private invitation
he has accepted
since becoming Reich Chancellor.
*he inhales with a hiss*
How did old Papen put it?
'I'll push him against the wall
until he squeaks.'
*distant gunshot*
Poor Schleicher.
I fear nothing will come of us.
*suspensefully pulsing music*
*clamor of voices*
What did she put down for me...
(laughing) Aha. Potatoes.
(Völcker)
Can we not reach an agreement?
No, we have already discussed this candidate.
We did not discuss him.
- Yes we did!
No, we are socialists.
We are capable of compromise.
(Helfers) We'll get nowhere like this!
We'll table the candidate list
and proceed with?
- (Litten) Roman numeral four.
Measures to stabilize democracy.
(Helfers) Thank you.
We envision a joint government
of the SPD and KPD...
- Just a moment.
It is our turn to propose first.
Alternating turns was the agreement.
- Correct.
Fine. Point one, then.
Petition to ban the NSDAP
as an unconstitutional party.
That is our point one as well.
- You see, it is possible.
*she hisses*
- Point two.
Nationalization of all corporations
supporting the NSDAP.
The Quandts, the Krupps, the Nyssens.
Proceed.
Point three.
Restructuring of the economic system
and the political order
along Soviet lines.
- Never!
We stand for a democratic economic model.
Which nobody wants,
because nobody believes in it!
That is why you lose votes with every election!
Because governing is harder work
than opposition!
Ha!
- One must make compromises.
You are driving the people
into the arms of the NSDAP!
Outrageous!
Order, ladies and gentlemen,
we cannot go on like this.
*chaotic roar of voices*
Pull yourselves together now!
Stop bickering!
This is sickening!
We cannot proceed this way.
If you place your factional interests
ahead of the greater good,
you will perish.
And rightly so.
People will say the Left failed
to stop Hitler
when they had the chance!
Because you are just as stubborn
as your party leaders.
Both of you!
(both) But I...
- If you speak now,
you will prove me right.
(Helfers) Where were we?
- (Völcker) Three.
Point four.
*tower bell tolls, chairs slide*
Herr Reich Chancellor.
My Führer.
Herr Hitler,
how wonderful that you made it
to our home after all.
We have much to discuss.
(Annemarie) She called him.
We have much to discuss,
my dear partner in crime.
Your wife called this new gentleman.
You are letting the reins slip from your hands.
On the contrary, I am taking them up again,
as you can see.
Helga supports me,
and I am very grateful to her for it.
Dear Adolf...
Dear Adolf Hitler,
we have much to discuss.
*metallic clatter*
*door creaks open*
*lamps hum*
*door closes*
Easy now.
Drink.
*he swallows, gasping*
*he breathes exhaustedly*
What do you want from me?
I can tell you exactly.
I want the medical file
of Lance Corporal Hitler
from his stay in Pasewalk
in November 1918.
*somber music*
I know nothing about it.
I doubt that.
I took Dr. Forster to Paris.
Not because of any file,
but because he needed protection.
From people like you.
You can waste your time
and beat whatever you want out of me.
Yet what you are looking for,
you will not find with me.
*tense, restless music*
Very well.
Then I wish you the best of luck
in the new German Reich,
as a personal enemy
of Reich Chancellor Adolf Hitler.
*footsteps recede*
*agitated clamor of voices*
*SA men shout indistinctly*
(SA Man) Langenberger! Camp North!
New arrivals, fall in here!
- Two more from cell 12.
All present.
Fall into line!
- Out now!
Let's move!
- That Heymann?
Jakob!
- Cell eight, move.
Katelbach, change of tracks.
Come with us now. Let's go.
(SA Man) Faster.
Move!
All hands!
What am I supposed to do with you now?
- Escape.
Stay with me
and wait for my signal.
Brock!
Let's go!
- Yes.
(SA Man) Look sharp!
Mandel!
Eckert!
Müllensiefen!
Heymann!
Heymann.
I'll take the older one,
you take the kid with the rifle.
Remember, on my command.
(SA Man) Ready up!
- Is everyone inside?
Mount up, quickly!
Czerwinski, Henning, depart!
Move, roll out.
*suspenseful music*
*indistinct shouting*
(SA Man) Halt! Identification!
All in order.
Henning! Czerwinski!
*he breathes with exertion*
*brakes squeal*
Halt!
Police, step out!
Out of the car!
Hey!
I'm sorry.
You cannot... that's impossible!
(Litten) Someone will be able
to tell me
where my clients
have been taken!
You call me back immediately
when you learn anything, understood?
Thank you!
Where on earth is Katelbach?
*nervously pulsing music*
What is going on here?
Holy...
*music turns more dramatic*
*engine roars*
*engine revs high*
Henning!
*he honks the horn*
Henning! Pull over!
What does that lunatic want?
Pull over!
*horn honks, tires squeal*
*he pants shakily*
What an idiot.
*music turns more restless*
(Heymann) Now.
Matern!
Shut your trap!
*music swells dramatically*
*tires screech*
(Heymann) Matern!
Grenadier, pull yourself together!
*gunshot*
- *Heymann screams*
What was that?
*sounds of fighting*
*tires squeal*
*chaotic shouting*
*music fades out*
Don't move!
I'll shoot!
(Langenberger)
Shoot! Shoot, boy!
*loud gunshot*
*she sighs*
Your weapon, quickly.
*hectic breathing*
Who are you?
*weary breathing*
*he laughs*
*he groans*
*he gasps for air*
*he speaks indistinctly*
The spuds.
Potatoes, I mean.
She always picks the floury ones.
*Katelbach wheezes faintly*
*Heymann chokes up*
*he breathes shakily*
*mournful violin music*
*music turns more tense*
This way no suspicion
will fall on you.
Are you sure?
Do you have a better idea?
Well, from your mouth to God's ear.
Best of luck, men.
*engine starts*
*mournful violin music continues*
*traffic noise*
*doorbell rings*
*sad piano notes*
Frau Behnke,
Katelbach and Heymann were
to be transported to a camp.
*piano drowns out dialogue*
He died in my arms.
You are injured.
Let me help you.
*Litten sobs*
(whispers) And there are more camps
outside the city?
(whispers) Yes. We suspect
in the north, just beyond the city limits.
How many inmates were there?
The more information I have,
the more I can accomplish in court.
In our cell there were twelve men.
In the entire compound,
perhaps 40 cells.
Some of them must have had
double occupancy.
*murmuring*
Frau Völcker, Frau Helfers...
it was a matter close to Herr Katelbach's heart
that your two parties find common ground
in this affair.
Therefore I would ask you
to reach a swift resolution.
Would that be possible?
*melancholy piano music*
(Woman) Women for Hitler.
Women for Hitler.
(Berlin dialect) Lotte? Hello there!
Oh, Doris.
Off work already?
How's it going?
I have a new job.
Women for Hitler.
Everything depends on us now.
(Berlin dialect) That over there?
No, that's voluntary.
No, something real. In radio.
Congratulations.
Yes, things are looking up for Germany.
I can see you're not convinced yet.
No, I'm not. Not at all.
You lack an eye for what matters.
I felt the same way in the beginning.
Yet believe me,
you'll see it differently soon.
The Führer is leading us all back home.
(snorts) I can find my own way there,
and right now, in fact.
Your rejection comes from the intellect.
Yet this is about feeling,
about security and love.
Love is the most important thing.
Yes, you may be right about that.
Yes, that's true, Lottchen.
Love,
love for Germany.
Doris, even when you talk nonsense,
I still love you.
Take care.
You too, Lottchen.
Sooner or later, you too will find
faith in a national awakening.
*departure whistle*
*wistful string music*
*she snorts*
*engine starts*
Charlotte?
*he sighs wearily*
*match hisses*
*faint thumping*
*he groans and wheezes*
*he wheezes*
*sounds of struggle*
*Döbrich groans*
*agonized screams*
*SA man groans in pain*
*he breathes frantically*
*he breathes shakily*
*he gasps for air*
*distant dog barking*
*gunshot*
*Döbrich groans*
*SA man collapses to the floor*
*gunshot*
*he breathes in panic*
Charlotte.
Gereon.
Döbrich.
Who is that?
Where were you?
Who are these men?
Charlotte.
Gereon, where were you?
No word! Nothing!
Stop it!
I was worried sick!
Just listen to me!
No!
You want to blow something up
and you make me an accomplice,
without saying a single word to me!
I've had it!
Charlotte.
I am so sick of not being able to trust you.
How do you know this man?
Works at the Burg.
We have to get out of here.
Charlotte, please.
We cannot stay here.
Where are we supposed to go?
*loud knocking*
Police, open up!
*doorbell rings*
Yes? Did something happen?
The neighbors report there was noise.
Here?
Well...
There were loud bangs!
And crashing like mad.
I drew a bath.
The water always splashes so loudly.
Would you like to step in for a moment?
I'll make us some coffee.
*constable clears throat*
No, no, young lady.
Enjoy your bath in peace.
A shootout looks quite different,
ladies and gentlemen, please.
Move along now!
Good day.
*gentle piano music*
*music turns darker*
Where is Dr. Forster?
In Paris.
Arrested?
No.
They only caught me.
Why didn't you ever reach out?
I did. Several times.
*she clicks her tongue in disbelief*
Charlotte, I...
*his breath catches*
*stately piano music*
*wistful violin music*
*